Vladislav Serkov

Moscow, Russia | +79853446858 | t.me/vladserkoff | vladserkoff@pm.com github.com/vladserkoff | linkedin.com/in/vladserkoff

Profile

Data scientist with hands-on experience in machine learning, statistical analysis, data visualization and big data. On one hand, I am capable of delivering results relevant to current business needs. And on the other hand, interested in a research for new data- and ML-driven products. My favorite tool for day-to-day work is Python, but I am also familiar with R.

Work experience

Senior data scientist at Dexpa: November 2018 - Present

Price and volatility prediction on crypocurrency markets.

Senior data scientist at Stream: September 2018 - October 2018

Stream is a division of MTS, one of Russia's largest telecommunication companies. There I've developed a face identification system for MTS' Second Memory service.

Senior data scientist at DCA: October 2017 - August 2018

DCA is a programmatic advertising platform and is one of the largest DMPs in Russia, seeing data from millions of sites every day. There I've built end-to-end systems that help to make sense of the data in unsupervised way:

1. Automatic audience segments creation based on target keywords;

2. Web pages categorization based on word2vec embeddings;

3. Audience look-alike segmentation;

4. Highload banner CTR prediction with Tensorflow and Tensorflow Serving.

Data analyst at R&D at Flocktory: November 2014 - September 2017

Designed and built data tools and products using Flocktory's data on activity of visitors of the majority of Russia's largest e-commerce sites. Products include (but not limited to): **1.** Matching product catalogs (taxonomies) of different shops onto a universal taxonomy; **2.** Identifying patterns in goods for promotions, e.g. the products that are purchased repeatedly; **3.** Building and maintaining dashboards and the data for the dashboards both for internal and external use.

Pricing analyst at Mamsy: March 2013 - November 2014

Mamsy is a e-commerce retail based on flash-sales model. In there I've decided on buying and selling prices based on expected costs, monitored and analyzed competitors' pricing.

Technical skills and programming languages

• Statistical skills: regression analysis, hypothesis testing, data visualization, association rules

- **Machine learning**: data cleaning and preparation, feature engineering, regression, classification, cross-validation
- Databases: Impala, Hive, HBase, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Vertica etc.
- Python: data munging with pandas, machine learning with scikit-learn, XGBoost and LightGBM, web scraping with requests, plotting with matplotlib and seaborn.
- Other tools: SQL for structured data, S3 and kafka for raw and stream data, parallel processing with dask library, Linux cli, cloud computing with AWS and Azure, version control with git, deploying to production with Docker.

Education

National Research University Higher School of Economics

Economist, with World Economy as the main field of study, Specialist: September 2008 - August 2013